welcome back to another video editing
欢迎回到另一个视频编辑
tutorial using the free software
使用免费软件的教程
kdenlive
克登利夫
in this video we're going to be learning
在这段视频中 我们将学习
how to animate objects will basically
如何为对象设置动画基本上将
animate text on the screen and so in the
使屏幕上的文本具有动画效果 因此在
last video we learned how to create a
上一个视频我们学习了如何创建
title screen so in this video we're
标题屏幕所以在这个视频中我们是
gonna do the same thing we're gonna
要做我们要做的事
click on this little triangle here this
点击这里的这个小三角形
drop down and go to add title clip and
下拉并转到添加标题剪辑和
we're presented with this box here and
我们在这里拿到了这个盒子
so now we're gonna do a title again so
所以现在我们要再做一次标题
we'll say this is TJ free and then and
我们会说这是TJ自由的 然后
if you remember from the last video I
如果你还记得上一段视频中的
made some changes so it remembers I mean
做了一些改变 这样它就会记住我的意思是
it'll keep the same style we did from
它将保持我们从
last time so now that's why it's red
最后一次所以现在这就是为什么它是红色的
with a green background and we can
以绿色为背景 我们可以
either come in here and we can zoom in
要么进来 我们就可以放大
on the object or we can just change the
对象上 或者我们可以只更改
font size and we can change what the
字体大小 我们可以更改
actual font is I'm gonna change this so
实际字体是我要更改它 所以
that it's not green we'll do maybe a
它不是绿色的 我们可能会做一个
blue border and we can change the
蓝色边框 我们可以更改
outline and make that a little bit
勾勒出它的轮廓 让它变得稍微
thicker if we want as well and then
如果我们想要更厚的话 然后
we'll change the color in the middle to
我们会把中间的颜色改成
white so now what's gonna look like this
白色 所以现在会是什么样子？
and actually against a black background
实际上是在黑色的背景下
if we come down here and click show
如果我们来到这里并点击显示
background this is what it'll actually
背景这就是它实际要做的
look like because we're creating a title
看起来像是因为我们正在创建一个标题
clip and there would have no video in
剪辑 就不会有视频
our in our project yet we just have this
我们在我们的项目中 但我们只有这个
text is all so we can hit OK and then we
文本就是一切 这样我们就可以点击OK 然后我们
have our title clip still nothing in our
我们的标题剪辑仍然没有在我们的
project but we can left-click bring it
项目 但我们可以左键点击带来它
down to video track 1 and we'll zoom in
向下到视频轨道1 我们将放大
a little bit on the timeline and if we
在时间线上有一点 如果我们
play this we'll see it just plays this
播放这个 我们会看到它只是播放这个
is TJ free that's all it does and then
TJ自由了吗？这就是它所做的一切 然后
it the video ends so we can actually
如果视频结束了 我们就可以
animate this and create it so it either
设置此动画并创建它 这样它就可以
maybe we want to come in from the bottom
也许我们想从头再来
you could create ending credits this way
您可以通过以下方式创建结束字幕
or you can have it slide in from the
或者你可以让它从
left or like to zoom in closer kdenlive
左侧或喜欢放大更近的kdenlive
it's a little bit interesting the way
这是一个有点有趣的方式
that it accomplishes this but we'll take
它能做到这一点 但我们会
a look and I'll show you how it works so
看一眼 我会告诉你它是怎么工作的
come back up here to our title clip if
如果出现以下情况 请回到我们的标题剪辑
you want to edit this text or anything
您想要编辑此文本或任何内容
we just double click and it brings us
我们只需双击它 它就会给我们带来
back into our double click over on this
回到我们在上面的双击
left hand side brings us back into this
左手边把我们带回这里
edit box
编辑框
so we can double-click and we can change
所以我们可以双击 然后我们可以更改
if you wanted to add like two
如果你想加两个
exclamation points to the end we can do
惊叹号到最后 我们能做的
that or even three and maybe we want to
甚至是三个 也许我们想
make we want this to be more centered so
让我们希望这个更集中 所以
we click on it when we have our
当我们有了我们的
selection tool selected and then we just
选择选择工具 然后我们只需
Center it like this analysis exactly in
就像这个分析一样 把它放在
the center of the of the viewer what are
观众的中心是什么
the things do we have up here we're not
我们在这里拥有的东西 我们并不是
gonna do that right now but we can we
我现在就会这么做 但我们可以
could add a rectangle so now we want to
可以添加一个矩形 所以现在我们想
go to this tab here for animation so we
请转到此选项卡查看动画 以便我们
click on the animation tab and we have a
单击动画选项卡 我们会看到一个
two buttons edit start and edit end so
两个按钮编辑开始和编辑结束SO
if we click Edit start we see everything
如果我们单击编辑开始 我们将看到所有内容
turns a little bit a shade of green and
变得有点绿色 然后
then we have this hand we can left-click
然后我们有一只手 我们可以左键点击
and drag and it moves around this this
然后拖着它绕着这个方向移动
box that says start on it there's
上面写着开始的盒子里有
another box that says end on it but
另一个盒子上写着结束 但
right now we're on edit start so we're
现在我们正在编辑开始 所以我们
only controlling the start box and I'm
只控制起始箱 而我
gonna zoom out just a little bit if we
如果我们把镜头拉近一点
come down here we can zoom out and see
到这里来 我们可以缩小视线 看看
what we're seeing so you can imagine
我们所看到的 所以你可以想象
this start box is actually what it's
这个开始框实际上就是它
like a camera kind of a camera angle or
就像一个相机 一个相机角度 或者
a camera view so that if we have it
一个摄像机视图 这样如果我们有它
start right here this is what the camera
从这里开始 这就是摄像机
is going to look at starting and since
将着眼于开始 因为
our start and our end we're in the same
我们的起点和终点我们是一样的
place no animation was taking place but
没有发生动画的地方 但是
if we move it down here we can move it
如果我们把它移到这里 我们就能把它移走
all the way off the screen the camera
摄像机一直从屏幕上消失
will start looking at just a bunch of
将会开始关注一堆
black and actually everything is black
黑色 实际上一切都是黑色的
if we click this show background it'll
如果我们点击这个显示背景 它将会
start here looking at a bunch of black
从这里开始看一堆黑色的
and then it'll end here with teeth this
然后它将在这里结束 带着牙齿
is TJ free text in the middle of the
TJ自由文本位于
screen that makes sense so I'm going to
这个屏幕很有意义 所以我要
leave it like this for now and it's
现在就让它这样吧 它就是
going to take the duration is five
要用的时间是五点
seconds so over five seconds it's going
几秒 所以超过五秒就开始了
to zoom up it's going to move up and
为了放大 它会向上移动
kind of create the effect of this text
某种程度上创造了这篇文章的效果
falling out of the top of the screen
从屏幕顶部掉下来
let's click OK and we'll see how that's
让我们点击OK 我们将看到这是如何
gonna work so we see this is TJ free and
会工作的 所以我们看到这是TJ自由的
there it is so at any point in the video
在视频中的任何一点都是如此
we can see now this text is moving we
我们现在可以看到这个文本正在移动我们
can go back in and edit that if we want
如果我们想的话可以回去编辑它
to maybe we didn't like that look so
也许我们不喜欢那样的样子
much about the animation tab
有关动画选项卡的更多信息
we can click Edit end or we can click
我们可以单击编辑结束 也可以单击
Edit start and we can move the start one
编辑Start 我们可以移动Start One
and have it be a little bit closer like
再靠近一点 就像
this because there's a lot of empty
这是因为有很多空的
space waiting for it to fall so we have
等待它坠落的空间 所以我们有
it be waiting waiting right above like
它就在头顶等着 就像
just barely ready to come in and we can
刚刚准备好进来 我们就可以
edit the end and for the end we can do
编辑结尾 对于结尾我们可以这样做
the same thing we can move it up here we
就像我们可以把它移到这里一样
can just kind of here to see what's
我可以在这里看看有什么
going on so now the end is going to be
所以现在一切都要结束了
now it's going to end with it completely
现在 它将完全以它结束
off the screen the ending screen is
在屏幕之外 结束屏幕是
going to look like this everything in
所有的东西都会变成这样
red so by the time the video ends this
红色所以当视频结束的时候
t.j free will be off the screen already
T.J FREE已经不在屏幕上了
hopefully this is making sense it's kind
希望这是有意义的 它是仁慈的
of hard to understand at first but it
一开始很难理解 但它
once you play with a little bit you'll
一旦你玩了一点 你就会
you'll see what it's doing so now we're
你会看到它在做什么 所以我们现在
playing it's gonna come here and keep
玩着它会来到这里 并保持
going and at by the time the clip ends
在剪辑结束时
it's off the screen again so that's how
它又从屏幕上消失了 所以这就是为什么
you can create an effect of text kind of
你可以创造一种文字的效果
falling off the screen like this we can
像这样从屏幕上掉下来我们可以
go back in if we want maybe we want to
如果我们想的话就回去 也许我们想
do a horizontal so we'd come here we go
做一个水平转弯 这样我们就会来到这里 我们走
to edit start which is down here now
要编辑现在位于下面的Start
let's zoom out a little bit let's have
我们把镜头拉近一点 让我们
it let's have our start to be over here
让我们从这里开始吧
towards the left and then click on edit
向左移动 然后点击编辑
end and let's have our end be over here
结束 让我们的尽头在这里
towards the right so now it'll start the
向右 所以现在它将开始
camera will start looking here and all
摄像机将开始在这里和所有地方寻找
this blackness we can click show
我们可以点击显示这片黑暗
background and see exactly what it'll
背景 看看它到底会是什么
look like
看起来像
and then it'll end it'll transition from
然后它将结束它将从
here over to here over a period of 5
从这里到这里在5年的时间里
seconds let's click OK and see how that
几秒钟后 让我们点击OK 看看如何
works go back to the start I'll play it
作品回到起点 我来演奏
and then we see a that since the camera
然后我们看到了一个 因为摄像机
is moving but we're just still seeing
正在移动 但我们仍然看到
this one view angle what it's creating
这一个视角是它所创造的
this effect of the text moving across
文本移动的这种效果
the screen something else we can do if
屏幕上还有其他我们可以做的事情 如果
we want to create an animation of the
我们想要创建一个动画
text starting really small and then
文本从非常小的开始 然后
becoming large again we have to do it
再次变大 我们必须做到这一点
all in this frame of reference like of
所有这一切都在这个参照系中
the size of this box so look we can
这个盒子的大小 所以我们可以
resize this down to 50% and then this
把这个调整到50% 然后这个
box becomes really small
盒子变得很小
so we can have it kind of actually let's
所以我们可以拥有它 实际上 让我们
make our n bot let's make this in 200%
制造我们的机器人让我们以200%的速度制造它
so let's zoom out and see so by the time
所以 让我们把镜头拉远 到时候再看看
it ends its going to be looking at here
它结束了 它将在这里看到
and then by the time when it starts I'm
然后当它开始的时候 我
sorry that was to start and then we'll
抱歉 这是开始 然后我们将
resize it by time it ends it'll be
根据它结束的时间调整它的大小
zoomed in really close to the text so
放大到离文本很近的地方 所以
it's gonna start really big like this
它会像这样开始非常大的
and it's gonna end really really tight
结局将会非常非常紧张
in like this so let's see if this
像这样 让我们看看这是不是
creates this kind of look we're going
创造出一种我们要去的样子
for
为
Oh sure enough so it starts to camp
哦 果然 它开始露营了
really far away and then over a period
真的很远 然后一段时间
of 5 seconds it gets very very very
在5秒内 它变得非常
close to this text pretty cool huh
接近这段文字很酷吧？
so that is using the again to get that
所以这就是再次使用来获得
we just added a title clip and there are
我们刚刚添加了一个标题剪辑 有
some templates and you can create your
一些模板 您可以创建您的
own templates you can there are some
自己的模板 你可以有一些
templates like this one that's a simple
像这样的模板是一个简单的
scroll kdenlive and if we do that one
滚动Kdenlive如果我们这样做的话
I'll just delete this clip so this
我要删除这段视频 所以这段
template just creates whatever text we
模板只是创建我们要创建的文本
type in and it just Scrolls from top to
输入 它就会从顶部滚动到
bottom just like that so if you want to
底部就像这样 所以如果你想
use a template and if you want to create
使用模板 如果您想要创建
your own title clip and then we could
你自己的片名剪辑 然后我们就可以
turn this one into a template not sure
将此模板转换为模板不确定
how how we actually make it a template
我们实际上是如何将其作为模板的
but I'm pretty sure we can add this into
但我很确定我们可以把这个加到
a template so now I'm off to figure it
一个模板 所以现在我要去想办法了
out and show you but I appreciate you
带你出去 但我很感激你
watching this video that's hopefully
观看这段视频 希望
giving you some ideas of how you can
给你一些想法 你可以
animate at least text and really what we
至少使文本和我们真正想要的
can end up doing it doesn't have to be
可以最终做到这一点并不一定是
just text so with there was this box for
只是发短信 所以有这个方框
drawing a shape we can draw a shape and
画一个形状我们可以画一个形状
then that'll actually animate on there
然后它就会在那里变得生动起来
as well it'll do whatever everything
同样 它会做任何事情
else was doing oh so if we drag this in
其他人都在做 所以如果我们把这个拖进来
then anything on that canvas anything
那么画布上的任何东西
that we were viewing will also become
我们正在观看的节目也将成为
animated or will be zooming in on that
动画或将放大该内容
as well so you can't animate individual
同样 你也不能将个人动画
objects at least not this using this
对象 至少不是这个对象
method but you can everything on this
方法 但您可以在此上执行所有操作
view will become animated according to
视图将根据以下内容变为动画
the this animation tab
此动画选项卡
and one more thing we can do we can
还有一件我们能做的事
actually add in pictures as well so you
实际上也添加了图片 这样你就可以
can add in an image like if we had this
可以添加一个图像 就像我们有这样一个
image of this top hat this has a
这顶大礼帽的图像 这顶帽子有一个
transparent background so it shows
透明背景 使其显示
really nice like this and it's also we
像这样真的很好 也是我们
can control the layer it's on here so it
可以控制它所在的层 所以它
can be behind the text if we want it to
如果我们想要 可以在文本后面
be and then that will also everything
是然后那也将是一切
will just get zoomed in there so if you
会被放大 所以如果你
have a logo that you want to add in with
我有一个您想要添加的徽标
your text you can do that as well
你的文本 你也可以这样做
hopefully this video has been
希望这段视频已经
informative thanks for watching don't
内容丰富的感谢收看《不要这样》
forget to comment like subscribe and
忘记像订阅和订阅一样评论
I'll catch you on the next video
我会在下一个视频中看到你